Guide to the Stephan Loewentheil photograph collection, 1822-1979.
Loewentheil, Stephan photograph collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Stephan Loewentheil photograph collection, 1822-1979.
8043
Loewentheil, Stephan,
circa 40.1 Cubic Feet.
Photographs, correspondence, photocopies, and manuscripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection of photographs on various subjects demonstrating the technological evolution of photography, with emphasis on the period of 1822 to 1885. Includes 19th- and 20th-century photographs organized in several major groups.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection of photographs on various subjects demonstrating the technological evolution of photography, with emphasis on the period of 1822 to 1885. Includes 19th- and 20th-century photographs organized in several major groups: Daguerre ephemera and early photographic processes, African American collection, Mathew Brady and the Civil War, Lincoln, Native Americans and the West, hand-colored photography, and cartes de visite. The collection contains daguerreotypes, salted paper photographs, ambrotypes, tintypes, albumen prints, cartes de visite, cabinet cards, stereographs, and photograph albums. Also included are lithographic prints (some hand colored), a graphite on paper portrait, wood engraving, medals, and stamp.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Loewentheil, Stephan,; Stephan Loewentheil History of Photography Collection.; Brady, Mathew B., 1823-1896; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1952
Subjects:
Daguerreotype -- History.; Photography -- History.; Indians of North America -- History.; African Americans -- Portraits.; Daguerreotype; Photography; Carte de visite photographs
Form and Genre Terms:
Ephemera.; Albumen prints.; Ambrotypes (photographs); Daguerreotypes.; Gelatin silver prints.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
By appointment only.
RELATED MATERIALS
An on-line exhibit of "Dawn's Early Light" showcasing many items from this collection.
An on-line exhibit of "Lincoln's Unfinished Work" showcasing many of the Lincoln related items from this collection.
NOTES
Associated book collection cataloged separately.
See the "Cataloged Separately" list at the end of this guide for a list of the CDV albums which have also been cataloged individually.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Daguerre and the History of Photography
Boxes I-1-8
Cased and Framed Photographs: Tintypes, Ambrotypes, and Daguerreotypes
Viewers and early animation
Series II. Cartes de Visite
Boxes II-1-15; Albums Cataloged as Bound Manuscripts
Alphabetical and By Subject
Brady, Lincoln, and the Civil War
Lincoln
Brady
Cartes de Visite viewers
Series III. Hand Colored Photographs
Boxes III-1-14
Series IV. African American
Boxes IV-1-39
Photograph Albums
Framed Photographs
Cased Photographs
Daguerreotypes and Ambrotypes
Tintypes
19th Century and Specialty Photographs
20th Century Photographs
Series V. Mathew Brady and the Civil War
Boxes V-1-26
Brady Daguerreotypes
Unattributed Daguerreotypes, and Brady Cases Without Images
Brady Ambrotypes and Tintypes
Other Brady Photographs
Engravings and Lithographs After Brady Photographs
Portraits of Brady and Brady Studio Receipts
Civil War Photographs
Brady's "Incidents of the War"
Brady's "Views in the Navy Ordinance Yard"
"Brady Photographs" and other photographs by Alexander Gardner
Photographs Attributed to Brady
Photographs by Brady and others
Historian George Sullivan's Mathew Brady Research Archive
Series VI. Lincoln
Boxes VI-1-6
Mapcase Folder 1
Series VII. New York History
Boxes VII-1-5; Album
Series VIII. Edward Curtis: Native Americans and The West
Boxes VIII-1-4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Daguerre and Early Photography
  - Semi-centennial of photography souvenir medal, 1889; Photographic Times; 4.7 x 4.7 cm; 1 medal (Box I-1, Folder 1)
  - Nicephore Niepce commemorative medal, 1885; 7 x 7 cm; 1 medal (Box I-1, Folder 2)
  - Portraits (Box I-1, Folder 3)
    - Stumbling Bear, Kiowa Chief, Fort Sill, 1869; 24.3 x 19.2 cm; 1 photograph; Mounted on board with handwritten description. (Box I-1, Folder 3)
      Portraits
      Albumen prints
    - Sir Henry Bessemer, 1881; Lock, Samuel R.; Whitefield, George C.; 27.3 x 20 cm; 1 print; Mounted on board. (Box I-1, Folder 3)
      Woodburytypes (prints)
    - Portrait of young man, 1860; 25.2 x 20 cm; 1 item (Box I-1, Folder 3)
  - Card photographs (Box I-1, Folder 4)
    - Daguerre, 1865; Cramer, G.; 16.5 x 11 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
      Reproduced from 1848 daguerreotype by Meade.
      cabinet photographs
      albumen prints
    - Young woman in plaid dress, 1865; F. Hall and Co.; 16.5 x 11 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
    - Louisa May Alcott, 1875; Conly's Studio; 16.5 x 11 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
    - Harriet Beacher Stowe, 1875; Sarony, Napoleon; 16.5 x 11 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
    - Helen Modjenka, 1875; Amie' DuPont Studio; 16.5 x 11 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
    - Colonel W.F. Cody (Buffalo Bill), 1885; Brisbois Studio; 16.5 x 11 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
    - Clearing the Channel, Cascades, Columbia River, Oregon, 1885; Watkins, Carleton E.; 21.5 x 13.7 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
      Columbia River, Oregon
      boudoir photographs
      card photographs (photographs)
    - Panorama of Portland, Oregon, 1885; Watkins, Carleton E.; 13.7 x 21.5 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 4)
      Portland, Oregon
  - Cartes-de-visite and calling cards (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Mrs. Prevost, 1875; Mayall, John Jabez Edwin Paisley; 22.6 x 17 cm; 1 sheet; Uncut sheet of four carte-de-visite images. (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Man with top hat and book, 1850; Disderi, Andre-Adolphe-Eugene; 20.2 x 23.3 cm; 1 sheet; Uncut sheet of eight carte-de-visite images. (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - W.W. Dow calling card, 1850; 9.1 x 13 cm; 1 sheet (Box I-1, Folder 5)
      Salted paper prints
    - H.G. Howell calling card, 1850; 4.5 x 8.7 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Calling card with three children, 1850; 6.1 x 9.7 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Eliza C. calling card, 1850; 5.5 x 8.8 cm; 1 card; Last name illegible. (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Samuel F.B. Morse, 1869; Brady, Matthew; 10.2 x 6.2 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
      Morse, Samuel F.B.
      cartes-de-visite (card photographs)
    - Self-portrait with chair, 1850-1859; Disderi, Andre-Adolphe-Eugene; 9.7 x 6.2 cm; 1 card; Signed. (Box I-1, Folder 5)
      Disderi, Andre-Adolphe-Eugene
    - Self-portrait, 1869; Fredericks, C.D.; 10.5 x 6.4 cm; 1 card; Initialed. (Box I-1, Folder 5)
      Fredericks, C.D.
    - Portrait of man with beard, Mason and Co. London; 10.2 x 6.4 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Oliver Wendall Holmes, 1860-1862; Black and Batchelder; 10.7 x 6.4 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
      Oliver Wendall Holmes
    - The Children of the Battlefield: Frank, Frederick and Alice, 1860-1864; Wenderoth, Taylor and Brown (Philadelphia); 10.2 x 6.3 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Portrait of woman, 1860; Silvy, Camille; 9.5 x 6.4 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Millie and Christine McCoy, 1860; W. and D. Downey; 10.4 x 6.3 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
      McCoy, Christine
      McCoy, Millie
      Conjoined twins
    - Millie and Christine McCoy, 1855; Germans, W.L.; 10.6 x 6.4 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Portrait of girl in costume with crown and scepter, 1865; Sheldon, J.A.; 10.3 x 6.1 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Man with rifle, 1870; 10.2 x 6.2 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Annie Leato Staynes (girl with curls), 1860; 10.4 x 6.3 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
    - Portrait of man with beard, 1865; Tilton, G. W.; 10.5 x 6.4 cm; 1 card (Box I-1, Folder 5)
  - Albumen and salted paper prints (Box I-1, Folder 6)
    - Le Cheval Abe Edgington, 1877-1878; Muybridge, Eadweard; 12 x 28.6 cm; Mounted on paper with annotations. (Box I-1, Folder 6)
    - West Point, 1865; Warren, George Kendall; 33.4 x 25.4 cm (Box I-1, Folder 6)
    - West Point, 1865; Warren, George Kendall; 25.4 x 33.4 cm (Box I-1, Folder 6)
    - Family in front of Niagara Falls, 1865; Mason, Samuel J.; 26.7 x 34 cm; Mounted on board. (Box I-1, Folder 6)
    - Louis Agassiz, 1845; 34.5 x 26.4 cm; Mounted on board. (Box I-1, Folder 6)
      Louis Agassiz
    - Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1845; 34.5 x 26.4 cm; Mounted on board. (Box I-1, Folder 6)
      Henry Wadswroth Longfellow
  - William H. Seward, 1861 (Box I-1, Folder 7)
    - Harper's Weekly featuring William H. Seward portrait, 1861; 40.4 x 28.5 cm; 1 newspaper (Box I-1, Folder 7)
      Engraving from a photograph by Matthew Brady.
      Engravings (prints)
    - William H. Seward portrait, 1861; 39.5 x 30 cm; 1 photograph; Photograph with applied color (Box I-1, Folder 7)
  - Daguerre ephemera (Box I-1, Folder 8)
    - L.J.M. Daguerre, 1835; Jackman, W.G.; 1 engraving (Box I-1, Folder 8)
    - Daguerre portrait, 1851; 1 drawing (Box I-1, Folder 8)
      drawings (visual works)
    - Daguerre portrait, 1837; 40 x 29.5 cm; 1 print (Box I-1, Folder 8)
    - Vue du Catheau d'eau Prise du Boulevard St. Martin, 1830; Basset; 1 print; Engraving with applied color. (Box I-1, Folder 8)
      View features Daguerre's Diorama.
    - Carte-de-visite order board, 1865; Sarony, Napoleon; 35.4 x 43 cm; 1 board; 2 large albumen prints, mounted recto and verso, featuring 56 carte-de-visite images (Box I-1, Folder 8)
  - The Elmira Cornet Band, 1861; Brady, Matthew; 26.7 x 36.5 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 9)
  - Charles A. Leale and family, 1880; Pach Brothers (Firm); 45.7 x 56 cm; 1 photograph (Box I-1, Folder 10)
    Charles A. Leale was the first physician to attend President Abraham Lincoln after Lincoln was shot at Ford's Theatre on April 14, 1865. This photograph shows the physician and his family at their home. Included are Dr. Leale, his wife Rebecca Medwin Copcutt Leale, and their children Annie, Lilian, Medwin, Marion, and Loyal.
    Leale, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1842-1932
  - Advertisements and illustrations, 1850-1887; 7 items (Box I-1, Folder 11)
    Four advertisements for photographic studios, a receipt from Brady's gallery, and two printed illustrations relating to daguerreotypes.
  - Cased and Framed Photographs: Tintypes, Ambrotypes, and Daguerreotypes
    - Photographic studio equipment, 1860-1865; 16.5 x 14 cm; Quarter plate, framed photograph with applied color. (Box I-2)
      Tintypes (prints)
    - Family (man, woman and five children), Circa 1855; Anson, Rufus; 22.8 x 17.8 cm; Whole plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-2)
      Daguerreotypes (photographs)
    - Union soldier, 1861-1865; 9.5 x 8.2 cm; Sixth plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
      Ambrotypes (photographs)
    - Man in red shirt, 1850; 9.5 x 8.2 cm; Sixth plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Girl holding apple, 1845-1855; 7.6 x 6.3 cm; Ninth plate, union case, photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Ten girls, 1855; 12 x 9.5 cm; Quarter plate, double cased photographs with applied color. (Box I-3)
      Names inscribed in pencil under photograph packets in case. On left: Emma Wickes, Jemma Boyd, Mary Hughes, Louise Muller, Clara Boyd. On right: Carrie Ferdinand, Sonia Draper, Harriet Muller, Ella Woods, Celia Nye.
    - John J. Halsey, 1844; Plumbe, John, Jr.; 9.5 x 8.2 cm; Sixth plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Woman wearing paisley shawl, 1840-1850; 12 x 9.5 cm; Quarter plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Man with dog, 1845-1855; 12 x 9.5 cm; Quarter plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Man and boy, 1852-1862; McClees and Germon; 12.7 x 10.2 cm; Stereo view, quarter plate, union case, photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Young woman with tassel in hair, 1850-1860; James and Co.; 11.4 x 10.2 cm; Ninth plate, framed photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Woman in bonnet, 1855-1860; Irving, James; Schoonmaker, C. C.; 9.5 x 8.2 cm; Sixth plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Three men, 1860-1870; 9.5 x 8.2 cm; Sixth plate, cased photograph with applied color. (Box I-3)
    - Civil War soldier in Union uniform, 1861-1865; 24.8 x 19.7 cm; Full plate photograph with applied color. (Box I-4)
    - Civil War soldier in Confederate uniform, 1861-1865; 25.4 x 20.3 cm; Full plate photograph with applied color. (Box I-4)
    - Two girls, 1855-1865; 20.3 x 14.6 cm; Oval photograph with applied color. (Box I-4)
    - Girl with blue dress, 1855-1860; 21 x 15.9 cm; Reverse print on glass. Applied color. (Box I-4)
  - Viewers and early animation
    - Hemisferium praxinoscope, Circa 1989-2010; MU-1512; This modern praxinoscope is decorated on the top and outside with a circus theme and the designation "hemisferium." The pictures on the strips to be viewed include dancing figures, tumblers, and a toy soldier on a rocking horse.; Invented by Charles-Émile Reynaud in 1877, the praxinoscope was an animation device, the successor to the zoetrope. It used a strip of pictures placed around the inner surface of a spinning cylinder. An inner circle of mirrors was placed so that the reflections of the pictures appeared more or less stationary in position as the wheel turned. The viewer looking in the mirrors would thus see a rapid succession of images, producing the illusion of motion.
- Series II. Cartes de Visite
  This series includes boxed CDVs. For the CDV albums that have been cataloged individually see the list at the end of this guide.
  - Single Images
    Alphabetical by name and by subject
    - A-Bra (Box II-1)
    - Bre-Co (Box II-2)
    - Cr-For (Box II-3)
    - Fos-Hei (Box II-4)
    - Hen-Ll (Box II-5)
    - Lo-M (Box II-6)
    - N-Ri (Box II-7)
    - Ro-T (Box II-8)
    - T-Z (Box II-9)
    - Varia (Box II-10)
    - Children (Box II-13)
  - Brady, Lincoln, and the Civil War
    - Lincoln (Box II-11)
    - Brady
      - Civil War officers (Box II-12)
      - Presidents of the United States (Box II-12)
      - Abraham Lincoln Related (Box II-12)
      - American Clergymen (Box II-12)
      - American Women (Box II-12)
      - Children (Box II-12)
      - American Actors (Box II-12)
      - American Notables (Box II-12)
      - Identified Men (Box II-12)
      - Unidentified Men (Box II-12)
      - Miscellaneous Cartes (Box II-15)
  - Cartes de visite viewers
    - Photographicon, 1865; MU-1511; Photograph viewer in the form of a wooden box covered in velvet, containing two rollers, with a viewing window on the top. By turning one of two knobs on the front of the device, the viewer can move forward or back through a roll of photographs on the two rollers. The roll contains many reproductions of engravings or lithographs in addition to (unidentified) portrait photographs. The images are in carte de visite format, but inserted into a continuous roll of paper photo frames. Images include a photo of a Union army officer from the Civil War.
- Series III. Hand-Colored Photographs
  - Framed Photographs
    - Portrait of a woman in a shadowbox frame with garland made from human hair. (Box III-1)
    - Woman with book, 1855-1865; 35.6 x 30.5 cm; Framed photograph with applied color. (Box III-11)
    - Girl, 1855-1865; 38.1 x 33 cm; Framed photograph with applied color. (Box III-12)
- Series IV. African American Photographs
  - Photograph Albums
    - 18 Photo albums (Box IV-1-18)
  - Framed Photographs
    - Framed Portrait (Box IV-21)
    - 2 Framed Portraits (Box IV-22)
    - 2 Framed Portraits (Box IV-23)
    - Framed Hand-colored Portrait of a Man (Box IV-33)
  - Cased Photographs
    - Daguerreotypes and Ambrotypes
      - Daguerreotype of African American nurse with two white children, infant’s dress painted blue., 1 (Box IV-25)
      - Pair of Daguerreotypes of African American nurse and three white children., 2 (Box IV-25)
      - Daguerreotype of African American nurse with two white children, 3 (Box IV-25)
      - Daguerreotype of African American woman in plaid shirt holding baby., 4 (Box IV-25)
      - Daguerreotype of African American woman with white child., 5 (Box IV-25)
      - Daguerreotype of African American woman wearing lace bonnet, striped bow., 6 (Box IV-25)
      - Daguerreotype of African American woman with bonnet., 7 (Box IV-25)
      - Daguerreotype of African American woman, seated, white collar., 9 (Box IV-25)
      - Daguerreotype of African American man with tie, 10 (Box IV-25)
      - Ambrotype of young African American woman with handkerchief in left hand. (Box IV-25)
      - Ambrotype of African American nurse with white infant. (Box IV-25)
      - Ambrotype portrait of a African American woman with 2 white children (Box IV-25)
    - Tintypes
      - Two white women and white child holding black rag doll. (Box IV-26)
      - Private Moses Keepson, 108th Kentucky, holding gun with bayonet fixed, and his wife, standing. (Box IV-26)
      - African American nurse and her two white charges. The nurse holds an infant in her lap. Standing next to her is a girl holding a child’s toy cart. (Box IV-26)
      - Mother (seated) and daughter (standing), the daughter’s dress painted blue. (Box IV-26)
      - African American woman with white boy and white infant. (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, waist-up, shirt with white buttons. (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, waist-up, shirt with white buttons (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, waist-up, shirt with white buttons (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, standing, through faux window. (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, standing, leaning on fence. (Box IV-26)
      - Woman with white infant. (Box IV-26)
      - Man, standing, holding cane, painted backdrop. (Box IV-26)
      - Man, standing, holding cane, leaning on carved chair. (Box IV-26)
      - Boy, standing, hat in hand, leaning on pedestal. (Box IV-26)
      - Two women, one seated, checked skirt, one standing, lace collar. (Box IV-26)
      - Couple, the man seated, the woman standing, painted backdrop. (Box IV-26)
      - Boy, standing, straw hat in hand, leaning on wood fence. (Box IV-26)
      - Fashionable woman, seated, tall hat, arms on tasseled cushion. (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, standing, with hat, cushioned stool at right. (Box IV-26)
      - Little girl, seated, stocking feet. (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, seated, waist-up. (Box IV-26)
      - Woman, seated, waist-up, puffy black sleeves. (Box IV-26)
      - African American girl with two white children. (Box IV-26)
  - Portraits, Snapshots, and Specialty Photographs
    - Buttons (Box IV-19-20)
    - Panoramic Photographs and Muybridge Prints (Box IV-24)
    - Highlights from the African American Series I (Box IV-27)
      King, Martin Luther Jr.
      Davis, Angela
      Ali, Muhammad
      Baker, Josephine
      Images were used as part of a web commemoration of Black History month in 2012.
      Includes portraits of Martin Luther King Jr., Angela Davis, Muhammad Ali, and Josephine Baker as well as images of sharecroppers, scenes from the Civil Rights Movement, and news photos of school integration.
    - Highlights from the African American Series II (Box IV-40)
    - Portraits and Snapshots (Box IV-28)
      - Photograph of William "Uncle Bill" Clark and copy of that photograph in a 1971 newspaper, Circa 1913, 1971 (Box IV-28, Folder 1)
      - 12 photographs removed from an album, Circa 1900 (Box IV-28, Folder 2)
      - 8 small portraits, 1 calling card, and 3 empty mats. (Box IV-28, Folder 3)
      - 12 CDV Portraits (Box IV-28, Folder 4)
      - 11 CDV Portraits, 1 small tintype portrait (Box IV-28, Folder 5)
      - 11 CDVs, 1 photograph (Box IV-28, Folder 6)
        Includes examples of caricature, black-face, and African American nannies with white children
      - 6 Tintype Portraits, 1 Tintype Caricature (Box IV-28, Folder 7)
      - 8 CDV Portraits, 1 Ferrotype Portrait, 2 Portraits (Box IV-28, Folder 8)
      - 12 Tintype Portraits (Box IV-28, Folder 9)
      - 9 Tintype Portraits (Box IV-28, Folder 10)
        Includes one with a African American woman and a white baby.
        Some in original matting.
      - 13 Tintype Portraits (Box IV-28, Folder 11)
        Includes a soldier, groups of students, and several of children
      - Lynchings (Box IV-28, Folder 12)
        Warning: contains graphic images.
      - Women's Groups, Circa 1950s (Box IV-28, Folder 13)
        Including one related to flowers or flower arranging.
      - Mainly images removed from photo albums (Box IV-28, Folder 14)
        Includes many cyanotype photographs.
        Images of farmers, groups, and servants.
      - 6 pages from a missionary calendar (Box IV-28, Folder 15)
      - Photographs of slave boys in the cane fields of Louisiana and a family in front of their home. (Box IV-28, Folder 16)
      - "Gwine to de Field" photograph of slaves by H.P. Monroe, Circa 1862 (Box IV-28, Folder 17)
        With 1971 letter from F. Van Deren Coke of the Eastman House
      - Photograph of man and young girl, Circa 1940s (Box IV-28, Folder 18)
        Published in "Snapshot" San Francisco Museum of Modern Art c. 1992
    - Small Prints (mainly in original matting) (Box IV-29)
    - Stereo Views (Box IV-30)
    - Medium prints (some in original matting) (Box IV-31)
    - Small Prints (some in original matting) (Box IV-32)
  - 20th Century Photographs
    - Interracial, Mugshots, Skin, Postcards, General Life (Box IV-34)
    - Military, Jotartt Jr. (Box IV-35)
    - Music, Film, Celebrities (Box IV-36)
    - Martin Luther King, Civil Rights (Box IV-37)
    - Family Life, Dental (Box IV-38)
    - Race Issues, Death Row, Tuskegee, Sports, Erotica (Box IV-39)
- Series V. Mathew Brady and the Civil War
  - Brady Daguerreotypes
    - Woman in Fur Coat and Hat, D-1; Half-length Seated Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Young Women, D-2-D-5; Four half-length Portraits (Box V-1)
    - Woman in Gingham dress, D-6; Half-length Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Man, D-7 (Box V-1)
    - Man, D-8; Half-length Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Older Woman, D-9; Three-quarter Length Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Woman, D-10; Three-quarter Length Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Small Child, D-11; Three-quarter Length Seated Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Man, D-12; Half-length Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Portrait of a Man, D-13 (Box V-1)
    - Young Woman, D-14; Three-quarter Length Standing Portrait (Box V-1)
    - D-15 (Box V-1)
    - Photograph of a Woman's Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Teenage Sisters in Gingham Dresses, D-17; Full Length Seated Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Man and Woman, D-18; Three-quarter Length Seated Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Young Man, D-19 (Box V-1)
    - Man Seated at Table, D-36; Three-quarter Length Portrait (Box V-1)
    - Men, D-21, D-25-26, D-37; 4 Bust Portraits (Box V-1)
    - Two Boys, D-22 (Box V-2)
    - Men, D-20, D-23-24, D-41-42, D-52; 6 Half-length Portraits (Box V-2)
    - Man, D-27; Half-length Portrait (Box V-2)
      Unidentified photographer
    - Young Boy, D-28; Three-quarter Length Standing Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Man with Glass, D-29; Half-length Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Woman, D-30; Half-length Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Older Woman with White Head Shawl, D-31; Half-length Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Young Man, D-32; Bust Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Man, D-33; Three-quarter Length Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Photograph of a Painted Portrait, D-38 (Box V-2)
    - Young Child, D-39 (Box V-2)
    - Man Wearing a Dark Cloak, D-40; Half-length Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Carlton Gates, D-43; Bust Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Man, D-45; Vignette Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Couple, D-46; Three-quarter Length Seated Portrait (Box V-2)
    - Woman, D-47; Bust Portrait (Box V-2)
  - Brady and Unattributed Daguerreotypes, and Brady Cases Without Images
    - Young Man, Bust Portrait; D-48, 1868 (Box V-3)
    - William Foster Day, a young man, seated portrait; D-49, 1868 (Box V-3)